The following content is provided under a
Creative Commons license. Your support will
help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to offer
high quality educational resources for
free. To make a donation or to view
additional materials from hundreds of MIT
courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare at ocw
.mit .edu. Well, OK. I'm happy to be back.
And I'm really happy about the project
proposals that are coming in. This is like,
OK, this is really a good part of the
course. And so keep them coming. And I'm
happy to give whatever feedback I can
on those proposals. And do make a start.
They're really good. And if some are
completed before the end of the semester
and we can produce a chance, offer you a
chance to report on them, that's good too.
So well done with those proposals. So
today, I'm jumping to part six. So part six
and part seven are optimization, which is
the fundamental algorithm that goes into
deep learning. So we've
got to start with optimization.
Picture. And then part seven will be the
structure of CNN's convolutional neural
nets and all kinds of applications. And so
can we start with optimization? So first,
could I get the basic facts about
three terms of a Taylor series? So that's
typical. It's seldom that we would go
up to third derivatives in optimization. So
that's the most useful approximation to a
function. Everybody recognize it? Here, I'm
thinking of f as just one function and x as
just one variable. But now, I really want
to go to more variables. So what do I
have to change if f is a function of more
variables? So now, I'm thinking
of x as, well, no, let me see.
Yeah, I want n variables here.
x is x1 up to xn.
So just to get the words straight so we can
begin on optimization. So what will be the
similar step? So the function f at x.
Remember, x is n variables. OK, now what do
I have? Delta x. So what's the point about
delta x now? It's a vector. Delta x1 to
delta xn. The derivative of f. It's a
vector, too. The derivative of f with
respect to x1, the derivative of f with
respect to x2, and so on. So what do I have
to change about that? And now, those guys
are vectors. So it's their dot product. So
it's delta x transpose,
that vector, times this df dx.
So now, I'm replacing this by all the
derivatives. And it's the gradient. So the
gradient of f at x
is the derivatives.
Let's see. It's essential to get the
notation straight here. Yeah. So it'll be
the partial derivatives of the function f.
So grad f is the partial derivatives of f
with respect to x1 down to partial
derivative with respect to xn. OK, good.
That's the linear term. And now, what's the
quadratic term? 1 half. Now, delta x isn't
a scalar anymore. It's a vector.
So I've got a function of f transpose and
a delta x. And what goes in between is the
second derivatives. But I've got a function
of n variables. And so what does this
mean? So now, I have a matrix of second
derivatives, right? And I'll call it h.
This is the matrix of
second derivatives.
f with respect to x, j, and xk. And what's
the name for this guy? The Hessian. Hessian
matrix.
How the Hessians got into this picture, I
don't know. The only Hessians I know are
the ones who fought in the Revolutionary
War for somebody. Which side were they on?
I think maybe the wrong side. The French
were on our side. And yeah, anyway, Hessian
matrix. And what are the facts about that
matrix? Well, the first fact is that it's
them. And the key
fact is it's symmetric.
Yeah. OK. And again, it's an approximation.
So and everybody recognizes that if n is
very large and we have a function of many
variables, then we had n derivatives to
compute here. And about half n squared
derivatives using the half comes from the
symmetry. But the key point is the n
squared derivatives to compute there. So
computing the gradient is feasible if n
is small or moderately large. Actually, by
using automatic differentiation, the key
idea of back propagation, back prop, you
can get,
you can do, you can speed up the
computation of derivatives quite amazingly.
But still, for the size of deep learning
problems, that's out of reach. OK. So
that's the picture. And then I will want
to solve, use this to solve equations. Let
me, there's a parallel picture for a vector
f. So now this is a vector function. This
is f1 of x up to fn of
x. And x is x1 to xn.
So I have n functions of n variables.
n functions of n variables. Well, that's
exactly what I have in the gradient.
That's, think of these two as parallel, the
parallel being f is, corresponds to the
gradient of f. n functions of n variables.
OK. So now maybe what I'm after here is
to solve f equals 0. So I'm going to think
about the f at x plus delta x.
So it starts with f of x. And then we have
the correction times the matrix of first
derivatives. And
what's the name for that
matrix of first derivatives?
Well,
if I'm just given n functions, and I,
yeah, what am I, what am I after here? I'm
looking for,
and I'm stopping at first order there. OK.
So that, these are the sort of like facts
of calculus. Facts of 1802, you could say.
Multivariable calculus, that's the point.
Notice that we're doing just like the first
half of 1802, just differential calculus,
derivatives, Taylor series. We're not doing
multiple integrals. That's not part of our
world here. OK. So that's the background.
Now I want to look at optimization.
OK. So over here,
I want to optimize, well, over
here, let me try to minimize
f of x.
And I'll be in the vector
case here. And over here,
I want to solve f equals 0. And of course,
that means, that means f of 1 equals 0 all
the way along to fn equals 0. Here
I have n equations and n unknowns.
Let me start with that one. And I'll start
with Newton's method. Newton's method to
solve these n equations and
n unknowns. OK. So Newton.
Newton's method.
Which is often not presented
in 1802. That's a crime.
Big application of gradients in Jacobians.
So I'm trying to solve n equations and n
unknowns. And so I want f at x plus delta
x to be 0. Right? So I want f of x plus
delta x to be 0. So f at x plus delta x is,
I'm putting in as 0. I'm just copying that
equation. Is f at where I am. Let me use
k for the case iteration. So I'm at a point
xk. I want to get to a point xk plus 1. And
so I have 0 is f of x plus j at that point
times delta x, which
is xk plus 1 minus xk.
Good. That's Newton's method. Of course, 0
isn't quite true. Well, 0 will be true for
the, I'm constructing xk plus 1 here. I'm
constructing xk plus 1. OK. So let me just
rewrite that. And we've got Newton's
method. So we're looking for this change,
xk plus 1
minus xk. I'll put it
on this side as plus xk.
So that's this. Now, I have to invert
that and put it on the other side of the
equation. So that'll go with a
minus. This guy will be inverted.
And f at xk.
So that's Newton's method. Natural. Let me
just repeat that. You see where the xk plus
1 minus xk is sitting. Right? And I moved f
of xk to the other side with a minus sign.
And then I multiplied through by j inverse.
So I got that. So that's Newton's method
for a system of equations.
And over there, I'm going to write down
Newton's method for minimizing a function.
This is such basic stuff that we have to
begin here. Let me even begin with an
extremely straightforward example of
Newton's method here. Suppose my function,
ah, suppose I've only got one function,
actually. Suppose I only have one function.
So suppose my function
is x squared minus 9.
And I want to solve f of x equals 0. I want
to find the square root of 9. So what is
Newton's method for it? We just should
see. My point is just to see how Newton's
method is written. And then rewrite it a
little bit so that we see the convergence.
So of course, the Jacobian is 2x. So
Newton's method says that xk plus 1. I'm
just going to copy that Newton's
method. Minus 1 over 2xk, right? That's the
derivative. Times f at xk,
which is xk squared minus 9.
OK. Followed the formula. This determines
xk plus 1. And let's simplify it. So here I
have xk minus, that looks like a half
of xk. So I think I have a half of xk. And
then this times this is 9
halves of 1 over xk. Is that right?
Half of xk from this stuff. And
plus 9 halves of 1 over xk. OK.
Can I just, like, check that I know the
answer is 3? Can I be sure that I get the
right answer, 3? So this, that if xk was
exactly 3, then of course I expect xk plus
1 to stay at 3. So does that happen? So
half of 3 and 9 halves of 1 third. What's
that? Half of 3 and 9 halves of 1 third.
OK. That's 3 halves and 3 halves. That's 6
halves. And that's 3. OK. OK.
So we've checked that the method is
consistent, which just means we kept the
algebra straight. But then the really
important point about Newton's method is to
discover how fast it converges. So now let
me do xk plus 1 minus 3. So now I'm looking
at the error, which is, I hope, approaching
0. Is it approaching 0? How quickly is it
approaching 0? These are the fundamental
questions of optimization. So I'm going to
subtract 3 from
both sides. Somehow.
OK. From here. I guess I'm going
to subtract 3. Can I just? So I was just
checking that it was correct. OK. Now, so
xk plus 1 minus 3. I'm going to subtract 3
from both sides. I'm going to subtract
3 there. And then I hope that that box is
what goes down here, right? Subtracted 3
from both sides. So I'm looking at the, I'm
hoping it go, now hoping things go to 0.
OK. So what do I have there? Let me factor
out the 1 over xk.
So what do I have then left?
1 over xk. So there's a 9 halves
from there. 1 over xk. So I really have
a half of xk. So I'm going to subtract xk
squared, because I've divided by an xk.
And this minus 3, I better put minus 3xk,
because I'm dividing by the xk. I
claim that that's, now I've got it.
And let's see. Let me take out the 2.
2, forget these 2's, and make that a 6.
So I have 1 over 2xk times 9 plus xk
squared minus 6. Anything good about that?
We hope so.
We hope that that is something attractive.
So this is, again, this is the error at
step k plus 1. And it's 1 over 2xk times
this thing. In brackets, 9 plus xk squared
minus 6xk. And we
recognize that as
xk minus 3 squared.
xk squared minus 6 of them plus 9. That's
xk minus 3 squared. OK. That was the goal,
of course.
The goal that shows why Newton's method
is fantastic. If you can execute it, if you
can start near enough, notice that, so
that's, so how do I describe this great
equation? It says that the error is squared
at every step. Squared at every step. So
if I'm converging to a limit,
it will satisfy the, it will be 3.
Or I guess minus 3. Is that possible?
Yeah. Minus 3 is another solution here. So
we're, so we've got two solutions. The
Newton's method could converge to 3.
Am I right? It could converge to minus
3? So I could, I'd have a similar equation
sort of centered at minus 3. Or
what, does it always do one of those?
It could blow up. It could, so that, so
those are, there are sort of regions of
attraction. They're all the starting points
that approach 3. And the whole point of
that equation is with quadratic
convergence, the error being squared at
every step, it zooms in on 3. Then there's
a whole, all these starting points that
would go to minus 3. And then there are
the starting points that would blow up. So,
and those, maybe for this very simple
problem, that, the picture is not too
difficult to sort out those three regions.
But if we had, and this is allowing for a
vector,
two equations or n equations, then we're
in n variables. And it's really, you get
beautiful pictures.
One of the type of pictures that gave rise
to these books on fractals, picture books
on fractals, to, for these basins of
attraction. Does the, does the starting
point lead you to one of the solutions?
Or does it lead you to infinity? Here, that
would be interesting to just draw it for
this. OK. But the essential point is the
quadratic convergence. If it's close
enough. Close. If xk is, if x0 is pretty
near 3, then this is about 1 sixth of
that. And there'll be a good region of
attraction in this case. OK. So that's,
that's Newton's method for equations. And
now I want to do Newton's method. I just
want to convert all those words over to
Newton's method for optimization. So
remember, the, the, these boards were
solving f equals 0. This board is
minimizing capital F. And what's the
connection between them? Well, of course,
when we, this, this corresponds to solving
the gradient equals 0. At a minimum, if I'm
minimizing, I'm finding a point where all
the first derivatives are 0. So, so that'll
be the match between these. That, that
this rad f in this picture is the small f
in that picture. OK. Now, I guess here I
have, and this is sort of the heart of
our applications of learning. We have very
complicated loss functions to minimize.
Functions of thousands or hundreds of
thousands of variables. OK. So that means
that we would like to use Newton's method,
but often we can't. Let, so let, so I need
to, to put down here two methods. One that
doesn't involve those high second
derivatives. And one, a Newton's that does.
So, so, so first, so, first I'll write down
a method that does not involve. So, so
method one.
And this will be
steepest descent.
And what is that? That says that xk plus
1, the new x, is the old x minus, Steepest
descent means that I move in the steepest
direction, which is the direction of the
gradient of f. I move some distance, and
I better have freedom to decide what that
distance should be.
So this is a step size s,
or in the language of deep learning, it's
often called the learning rate. So if you
see learning rate.
OK.
So is that, that, so, and it's natural to
choose sk. We're going along, do you see
where, what this right hand side
looks like? I'm at a point in n dimensions.
We're all, all, we're in n dimensions here.
We have functions of n variables. There is
a vector. There is a direction to move down
the steepest slope of the, of the graph.
And here is a distance to move. And we
will stop. We'll have to get off this step
normally.
If we, if we stay on it, it'll sway, it'll
swing back, it'll, you know, take us off to
infinity. We, the, the, you would like to
choose sk so that you minimize capital F.
You, you take the point on this line. So
this is, I'm, I'm, this is a line in, in,
in Rn. A direction in Rn. And for all the
points on that line, in that direction, F
has some value. And what you expect is that
initially, because this, because you chose
it sensibly, the value of F will drop. But
then at a certain point, it'll, it'll turn,
turn back on you and, and increase. So that
would be the natural stopping point. That
would, I would call that an exact line
search. So exact line search would be,
exact line search
is the best S.
Of course, that would take time to,
to compute. And you probably, in deep
learning, that's time you can't afford.
So you fix the learning rate S. Maybe you
choose 0 .01 to be pretty safe. OK. So
that's method 1, Steve. Now, method 2 will
be Newton's method.
So now we have xk
plus 1 equal to xk minus
something times delta F.
And now I'm going to do the right thing.
I'm going to live right here. And the right
thing is the Hessian, the second
derivative. That's what, this, this was
cheap. We just took the direction and, and
went along it. Now we're getting really the
right direction by using the
second derivative. So that's H inverse.
OK. And what I've done is to, is
to set that to 0. So that would be,
do you see that's Newton's method? It's
totally parallel to this guy. Actually, I'm
really happy to have these two on the board
parallel to each other. Because you have
to kind of keep straight. Are you solving
equations? Or are you minimizing functions?
And you're using different letters in the
two problems. But now you see how they
match. The Jacobian of,
so, so again, the match is F. Think of F as
the gradient of F. That's, that's the way
you should think of it. So the Jacobian
for, of the gradient is the Hessian. The
Jacobian of the gradient is the Hessian.
And that makes sense because we're taking,
the first derivative of the first
derivative is the second derivative. Only
we're doing matrix -wise. So that's, so
the Jacobian of the gradient, we're doing a
vector matrix sentence instead of a scalar
sentence. The Jacobian of the gradient is a
Hessian. Yeah. Right. OK. So that's what
I wanted to start with. Just to get those
basic facts down. And so the basic
facts were the, were the three -term Taylor
series. And then the basic algorithms
followed naturally from it by setting the
F, F at the new point to 0, if that's what
you were solving. Or by assuming you had
the minimum. Right. Good. Good, good, good.
OK. Now what? Now we have to think about
solving these problems, studying do they
converge? What rate do they converge? Well,
that's, the rate of convergence is like
what I, why I took this, separated off this
example. So the convergence rate for
Newton's method will be quadratic. The
error gets squared.
And of course, that means super fast
convergence if you start close enough. The
rate of convergence for a steepest descent
is, of course, not. You're not squaring
errors here because you're, you're just
taking some number instead of the inverse
of the correct matrix. So
you, you, you can't expect
super speed. So a linear rate of
convergence would be right. You expect that
the error to, you would like to know that
the error is multiplied by, at every step,
by some constant below 1. That, that
would be a linear rate compared to being
multiplied by, being squared at every step.
OK. And so this will be our, our basic,
this is the basic formula
that, that we build
on for, for, for large scale, for really
large scale problems. And there are
methods, of course, people are going to
come up with methods that, they're sort of
a cheap Newton's method. Levenberg
-Marquardt, and it's in the notes at the
end of this section, at the end of the 6 .4
that we'll get to. So Levenberg -Marquardt
is a sort of cheap man's Newton, Newton's
method. It does not compute the Hessian,
but it, but it says, OK, I, I, from the
gradient, I can see a sort of one term in
the Hessian. So it grabs that term. But
it's not fully, fully second order. OK. So
now we, now we have to think about
problems. And I guess the whole, the, the
message here is, and our starting point has
to be convexity. Convexity is the key word
for this, for these, for these problems.
For the, the function that we want to
minimize, if that's a convex function,
well, first of all, the convex function is
likely to have one minimum. And the picture
that's in our mind steepest descent, this
picture of a bowl. A bowl is the graph of
a convex function. So that, so I'm turning
to convexity now. I'll leave that board
there, because that's pretty crucial.
And speak about
the idea of convexity.
Convex function, convex set.
So let's call the function f of x. And the
typical convex set will be, I'll call it k.
OK.
So we just want to remember what does that
word convex mean? And how do you know if
you have a convex function or a convex set?
OK. Let me start with convex set. So it's,
because here's my general
problem. My convex minimization.
Convex. And so let me draw a convex
function, the graph. OK. So I'll draw a
convex function, say a bowl. So that's a
graph of f of x. And then, so here are the
x's. Let me, maybe put x1 and x2 in the
base. And the graph of f of x1, x2 up here.
OK. Actually, I'm over there. I should
be calling this function f, I think. Is
that right?
Yeah. Little f would be the gradient
of this guy. Yeah, I think so. I won't.
OK.
But now I'm minimizing over x in,
over certain x's, not all x's. I might be
minimizing, for example,
k might be the set
where Ax equals b.
k might be, in that case, a subspace. Or a
shifted subspace, when I said subspace, but
then 1806, is reminding me in my mind that
I only have a subspace when b is 0. But I
have a, you know the word for a subspace
that's sort of moved over? Affine. So I'll
just put that word down.
Bunch of words to learn for this topic. But
they're worth learning. OK. So it's like a
plane, but not necessarily through the
origin. If b is 0, it doesn't go through.
If b is not 0, it doesn't go through the
origin. OK. Anyway, or I have some other
convex set. Let me just put this
convex set k in the base. And did
I make it convex? I think pretty luckily I
did. So now what's the, well, the convex
set, the constraint. So this is
the constraint. The set constraint
is that x must be x is in the set k. OK.
And I drew it as a convex blob. Here was an
example where it's a flat, not a blob, but
a flat plane. But what does, let me come
back to what does convex mean. What's
a convex set? Well, we have to do that.
Should have done that before.
In the notes, I had the fun of figuring
out if I took two, if I took a triangle, is
that a convex set?
Let's just be sure.
So what's a convex set? That is a convex
set because if I take any two points in the
set and draw the line between them, it
stays in the set. So that's convexity. Any
edge line from x1 to x2
stays in the set. OK. Good.
So I've exercised to myself. What if I took
the union of two triangles? All I wanted
to get you to do is to sort of visualize
convex and not convex possibilities.
Suppose I have one
triangle. Even if it was obtuse,
that's still convex, right? No problem.
But now what if I put those two triangles
together, take their union? Well, if I take
them sitting with a big gap between, like
I've lost. I mean, I've never had a chance
that way. Because if I took one of my, if
it was the union of these two, well, you
know what I'm going to say. If I took that
point and that point, of course, it goes
outside and stupid. All right. But what if
the triangles, what if that triangle, that
lower triangle kind of overlaps the upper
triangle? Is that a convex set?
Everybody's right, saying no. How do I say
that the union of those two triangles is
not a convex set? Because you tell me where
to pick two points where the line goes
out. Well, I take one from that corner and
one from that corner and the line between
them went outside. So
union is usually not convex.
Well, if I think of the union of two sets,
my mind actually automatically goes to the
other corresponding possibility, which is
the intersection of the two sets. So if I
take the intersection of the two sets. Now,
what's the deal with that? When I had two
triangles, two separated triangles, what
can we say about the intersection of those
two triangles? It's empty. So should we
regard the empty set as a convex set? Yes.
Isn't it? Yes, it's vacuum. It's vacuous.
So it hasn't got any problems, right? OK.
But now, is the intersection is always
convex? I'm assuming the two sets that we
start with are. Now, that's an important
fact, that the intersection of convex sets.
Let's just draw a picture
that shows an example.
So what's the intersection? Just this part,
and it's convex. OK. Can you give me a
little proof that the intersection is
convex? So I take two points in the
intersection. Let
me start the proof.
To test if something's convex, how do you
test it? You take two points in the set, in
the intersection, and you want to
show that the line between them is in the
intersection. OK. Why is that? So take
two points. Take x1 in the intersection of,
we've got two sets here, and that's the
symbol for intersection. And we've got
another point in
the intersection.
And now we want to look at the line between
them, the line from x1 to x2. What's the
deal with that one?
Is that fully in x1, in k1?
Why is it fully in k1? I took two points in
the intersection. I'm looking at the line
between them. And I'm asking, is it in
the first set, k1? And the answer is yes,
because those points were in k1, and k1's
convex. And is that line between them in
k2? Yes, same reason. The two endpoints
were in k2, so the line between them is in
k2. So the intersection of convex sets is
always convex. The intersection of convex
sets is convex. Good.
So you'll see in the notes these
possibilities with two triangles. There's
sometimes you can take the union, but
not very often. Now what's the next thing I
have to do?
Convex functions. We've got convex sets.
What are convex functions? Then we're good.
Right, because this is our prototype of a
problem. And I now know what it means to be
for that f to be a conv. No, I'm sorry. I
now know what it means for the set k to be
convex set. But now I have to look at
the other, often more important part of the
problem. What's the function I'm
minimizing? And I'm looking for functions
with this kind of a picture. OK. The
coolest way is to connect the definition of
a convex function to the definition of a
convex set. This is really the nicest way.
It's a little quick. It just switches by
you. But tell me, do you see a convex set
in that picture?
Do you see a convex set in that picture?
That's the picture of a graph of a convex
function. It's a picture of a bowl. Are the
points on that surface, is that a convex
set? No, certainly not.
But where is a convex set to
be found here in that picture?
Yes? The set of y, the set of y is greater
than the set of y. Yes, the points on and
above the bowl, inside the
bowl, we could say. These points.
So convex function, yes, functions convex
when the points are on and above the graph
are a convex set.
This is, you could say, OK, mathematicians
are just being lazy, having got one
definition straight for a convex set.
Using that to give an easy definition of a
convex function. Actually, it's quite
useful for functions that could maybe equal
infinity, sort of generalized functions.
But it's not the quickest way to tell if
the function is convex. It's not our usual
test for convex functions. So now I want to
give such a test. OK.
So now I, definition.
Of convex function.
Of a smooth convex function. Yeah, this
fact, I shouldn't rush off away from it.
From the definition of a convex function
as having a convex set above its graph, the
really official French name for the set
above the graph is the epic graph. But I
won't even write that word down. OK. Why do
I come back to that for a minute? Because
I would like to think about
two functions, f1 and f2. Out of two
functions, I can always create the minimum
or the maximum.
So I could choose two functions,
convex functions f1 and f2.
OK. Then I could choose the minimum. I
could choose my new function. Shall I call
it little m for minimum? m of
x is the minimum of f1 and f2.
And I could choose a maximum function,
which is the maximum of f1 of x and f2 of x
at the same point x. It's just a natural
thing. OK. I have two functions. I've got a
bowl and I've got another bowl.
And suppose they're both convex.
So I'm just stretching the thing here. I've
got the graphs of two convex functions. I
would like to consider the minimum of
those two functions and also the maximum of
those two functions. I believe life is
good. One of these will be convex and the
other won't. And can you identify which
one is convex and which one is not convex?
What about the minimum? Is that a convex
function? So just look at the graph. What
does the minimum look like?
The minimum is an
independent periodic function,
There's no proof. There is the maximum
function. That was the minimum function. It
had a kink. The maximum function is like
that, and it is convex. So maximum, yes.
Minimum, no.
And we could have a maximum of 1 ,500
functions. If the 1 ,500 functions are all
convex, the maximum will be, because it's
the part way above everybody's graph. And
that would be the graph of the maximum. OK,
good. And now, finally, let me just say,
how do you know whether a function
is convex? How to test. How to test.
OK, so let me take just a function of
one variable. What's the test you learn in
calculus, freshman calculus,
actually, to show that this
is a convex function?
What's the test for that?
Second derivative should be positive,
or possibly 0. So second derivative
greater or equal 0.
That's convex.
OK, final question. Suppose f is a vector.
So this is a vector. And so I have n
functions of n variables. No, I don't. I
have one. Sorry, I've got one function. But
I'm in n variables.
So this was just one.
What's the test for convexity?
So it would be passed, for example, by x1
squared plus x2 squared. Would it be passed
by? So here would be the question. Would
it be passed by x transpose some symmetric
matrix S? That would be a
quadratic, a pure quadratic.
Would it be convex?
What would be the test?
I'm looking for an n -dimensional
equivalent of positive second derivative.
The n -dimensional equivalent of positive
second derivative is convexity. So I'm
going to have to figure out what's the
test. So I could apply it to this function,
or I could apply it to any
function of n variables.
And I maybe should be OK.
What's the test here? Here I have a
matrix instead of a number. So what's the
requirement going to be? Hessian is
supposed to be definite? Positive definite,
or semi -definite. Or semi -definite just
as here. Yeah. So the test is positive semi
-definite Hessian.
And here the Hessian is actually that
S, because the second derivatives will
produce. I'll put a half in there. The
second derivatives will produce S equal the
Hessian H. So this here, the S. So positive
semi -definite Hessian in general, second
derivative matrix for a quadratic. So it's
convex problems where we're going to get
farther with. We run into no saddle points.
We run into no local minimum. Once we
found the minimum, it's the global minimum.
These are the good problems. OK. Again,
happy to see you today. And
I look forward to Wednesday.